# Gaspare Frazzitta

### Product UI/UX Designer

+44 (0)751 0525438 gaspfrazz@hotmail.it London



### Professional profile

#### **About me**

UX/UI product designer with an extensive experience in creating intuitive products that cater to both user needs and business goals. I'm also an expert in delivering best in class user interfaces, animations and branding for apps and web platforms.

#### **Skills**

I have experience in planning and executing workshops, creating flowcharts and feature maps, conducting competitor analysis, running user interviews, and crafting wireframes and prototypes. I advocate for collaboration and consistently work as a team player alongside PMs, engineers and UX researchers.

I excel in user interface design with a pixel-perfect mindset. Over the years, I've refined my skills in Figma, contributing to the development of atomic design systems for both large and small clients. Additionally, I am an advocate for Figma's latest technologies, including auto layout and in-depth high-fidelity prototyping.

## Experience

#### 2022 - today

#### Senior UX designer at Indeed

Indeed, with it's global reach and commitment to connecting job seekers and empleyers, is the world's leading job search platform. My primary responsibility is leading the design & experience of the Indeed Flex Client Portal, which serves major clients like Sainsbury's in the UK and Tesla in the US. Additionally, I provide mentorship to a team of designers within the same domain.

#### 2021-2022

#### Lead Product designer at Zego

Zego is a commercial motor insurance that combines best tech with sophisticated data sources to offer insurance product that save business and customers time and money. I contributed to the ideation, creation & release of Zego first driver score feature & the full scale 5 stars app Zego Sense for iOS & Android. I led & line managed the Product Design team enhancing the collaboration with UX Researchers, Product Managers, Engineers and Stakeholders to deliver the best in class products. In the last quarter I also contributed at shaping the app strategy vision for the 2023

#### 2014-2020

#### **Head of Product Design & UX**

TouchNote is a mobile app for smartphones, tablets and website for sending printed, personalized products. I led product design and creative branding direction, contributing to a membership model with 150,000+ members, successful in-app features, 15 millions cards sent worldwide including the Good Web Guide's App of the Year 2018 and Financial Times Tech 100 Europe.

#### **Awards**

Fastest-growing tech company in the UK - The Deloitte Tech Zego

Top 50 - 11th position - 2021

Major Influencer Campaign - The Major Players 2018 TouchNote Studio team **TouchNote** 

Technology Fast 50 Deloitte UK, Everline future 50 2016, BMA platinum nominee

3rd prize app at Microsoft UK, Publish 2015 in London. **Clippy Notes** 

House Finder Most innovative app from AppCampus.fi at MWC Barcelona 2015

### More about me

**Education** 2017 - Media Training London, UK

Motion Design | After Effects CC.

2016 - General Assembly London School, UK

User Experience design campus.

2010 - 2013 Academy of Fine Arts, Florence, Italy

Bachelor of Arts: Graphic Design

Languages Italian (native), English, Spanish (basic).

**Hobbies** I love cooking and I am a tea addicted. I also enjoy dabbling in social media and have transformed my cat into an "Instagram wannabe influencer" under the handle @MrChonkes.

Additionally, I have a deep appreciation for history, coin collecting, interior design especially

midcentury modern design.